

I am motivated, solution driven, professional and organised. I deliver the highest quality web solutions as evidenced by my extensive work experience and academic achievements. I strongly believe in the power of teamwork and being a speaker of English, German and Polish I thrive in multicultural work environments.

I would be excited to advise and work with enterprises in the Berlin and Hamburg regions.



+49 (0) 176 67 5279 05



czerasz.job@gmail.com



czerasz.job



www.czerasz.com

www.linkedin.com/in/czerasz

Skills

Back-End Programming Languages

- Ruby
- Python
- Javascript Node.js
- PHP
- Bash

Other

- Linux, Cloud, CDN, Architecture, Scalability
- Varnish, Nginx
- Docker, Vagrant, Ansible, Puppet

Developments methodologies

- Kanban, Scrum
- TDD

Data Stores

- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Elasticsearch
- Redis

Front-End Technologies

- HTML5
- Sass/Compass
- Javascript, Grunt, Angular

Education

2005 - 2010

+ Masters in Computer Physics

University of Science and Technology in Kraków, AGH

Achievements:

Recipient of a scholarship for academic achievements and grade point average in the top 10% of the year group

Subjects Included:

- econophysics, computer simulations in physics
- web development, databases, UNIX operational systems
- nuclear physics, quantum mechanics, statistical mechanics

Working Experience

2013/03 - 2015/01 + Senior Software Developer, Team Leader

castaclip GmbH | Berlin, Germany

Maintenance of an infrastructure which serves over 79 mln page views per month.

Responsibilities:

- root cause analysis and problem resolution
- solving software issues which affect the system and servers
- design and development of Front-End architecture
- Back-End development in Ruby, Python and PHP
- Ansible integration
- integration of Monit into systems
- setup and maintenance of MongoDB and Elasticsearch clusters
- active involvement in the recruitment process
- configuration and integration of CDN
- writing of scripts to automate work processes
- involvement in graphical design process and content strategy
- participation in IT related conferences and Meetups

2012/02 - 2013/03 + **Developer**

castaclip GmbH | Berlin, Germany

We were able to overcome most obstacles and move forward with the roadmap.

Responsibilities:

- management and development of existing infrastructure
- development of REST API based on Ruby stack
- implementation of JSONP layer using Varnish
- setup of the Elasticsearch cluster

2010/01 - 2012/02 + Web Developer

Credit Suisse | Wrocław, Poland

Working on various online-marketing campaigns in cooperation with German-speaking business partners from Zurich.

Responsibilities:

- development of complex forms in JSP, HTML/CSS and Javascript
- creation of dynamic Flash banners
- planning and execution of web performance audits
- implementation of web application tracking

2010 - 2011

+ Web Developer, Graphic Designer

Hidden Data | Kraków, Poland

Responsible for ideas generation, design of posters and various print materials. During this time I learned that communication is key to making a project successful.

Responsibilities:

- creation of wireframes and layouts view portfolio
- Front-End development
- work on numerous print projects
- development and implementation of the visual concept for the student event "Juwenalia 2010"

Certifications

- PRINCE2 Foundation Examination
- MongoDB Certified Developer Associate Level Exam

Courses

- M102: MongoDB for DBAs, M101JS, M101J
- Digital Analytics Fundamentals: Google Analytics Academy
- Google Analytics Platform Principles

Languages

English: professional working proficiency

German: bilingual proficiency

Polish: native proficiency